Guide to the Collection of Spanish Bookplates
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Spanish bookplates
1500-1984
1900-1950
BKP 45
Yale University Arts Library
5.42
(13 boxes)
The collection contains examples of bookplates by Spanish artists as well as those commissioned by Spanish patrons.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains examples of historical and modern Spanish bookplates. These ex-libris are either by Spanish artists or commissioned by Spanish patrons.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Bookplates – Artists & Individuals. II. Bookplates – To be filed. III. Bookplates – Miscellaneous. IV. Bookplates – Barcelona.
Bookplates, Spanish; Bookplates
- Bookplates – Artists & Individuals, 1875-1984; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by the artist's or individual's last name. Artists' folders are separated and marked as such, as per the original order. Please note that the separation of artists and patrons may, on occasion, interrupt the alphabetical ordering of the series.
  - A – Almeida, 1901-1938 undated; 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abad [Artist Folder], 1944-1952 undated; 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Abel [Artist Folder], 1920; 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alcina Munné, Herme [Artist Folder], 1946; 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - de Alos – Arrojo, 1950-1957 undated; 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alpresa [Artist Folder], 1950-1959 undated; 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anglada-Villá [Artist Folder], 1946-1958 undated; 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arce, D. R. [Artist Folder], 1946; 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Arias, Joze [Artist Folder], 1944; 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Augustana – Balaguer, 1947-1952 undated; 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bac [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Balcárek – Barcelona, 1950 undated; 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bardino – Bastos, 1913-1933 undated; 18 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Batlle – Batlló, 1947 undated; 36 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baucis – Bendoraitis, 1913-1948 undated; 22 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Beltrán Fornés, Vincente [Artist Folder], 1948; 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Blanco del Pueyo [Artist Folder], 1940-1941 undated; 7 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Berasategui – Blanch de Castillo, 1931 undated; 12 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Boada – Botta, 1935-1948 undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bon [Artist Folder], 1947-1948 undated; 10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Borrell [Artist Folder], 1924-1953 undated; 41 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - de Botella [Artist Folder], 1921-1952 undated; 28 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Budan – Cañete, 1902-1953 undated; 20 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Caniceiro – Cardoso Gonçalves, 1955-1956 undated; 30 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Carmo – Castells, 1883-1949 undated; 15 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Catala – Catasús, 1914-1951 undated; 24 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Calyo [Artist Folder], 1945 undated; 2 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cardeñosa [Artist Folder], 1951-1953 undated; 6 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Cardunete [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Carmier [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Casals y Vernis [Artist Folder 1 of 2], 1913-1917 undated; 25 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Casals y Vernis [Artist Folder 2 of 2], 1899-1919 undated; 26 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Castellar, J. [Artist Folder], 1948 undated; 3 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Carló - Casademunt, 1875-1917 undated; 10 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Castelló, A. [Artist Folder], undated; 5 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Castells [Artist Folder], 1923 undated; 10 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ceballos – Comas, 1918-1950 undated; 24 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Chaves, J. R. [Artist Folder], 1941-1948 undated; 22 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Chorro, J. [Artist Folder], undated; 6 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Collet, Carlos [Artist Folder], 1948 undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Comin – Cordeiro, 1944-1967 undated; 12 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Contente, J. [Artist Folder], 1948; 1 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Corcho [Artist Folder], 1944 undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Corderas, A. [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Cordova – Cusi, 1899-1950 undated; 31 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Corin [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Coromina, D. [Artist Folder], 1905; 1 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Cortes, G. [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - D – Dutra, 1939-1949 undated; 21 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Dalmau [Artist Folder], 1916-1953 undated; 60 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Diaz, Esther [Artist Folder], undated; 3 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Diaz, J. B. [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - E – Estevez, 1931 undated; 31 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Esteve, Francisco [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Estiarte [Artist Folder], 1939-1950 undated; 20 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Fabregas – Fargas, 1914-1917 undated; 20 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Falgas [Artist Folder], 1917-1948 undated; 34 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Faria – Ferrer, 1919-1931 undated; 28 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Figueras – Furtado, 1918-1957 undated; 24 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Figuerola [Artist Folder 1 of 2], 1907-1920 undated; 24 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Figuerola [Artist Folder 2 of 2], undated; 25 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Furió [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - G – Garcia, 1927-1952 undated; 24 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Gaci, J. [Artist Folder], 1942; 1 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Garcés [Artist Folder], 1903 undated; 8 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Garriga – Gimenez, undated; 21 items (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Garró [Artist Folder], 1944; 1 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Gavilan [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Gelabert [Artist Folder], 1951-1960 undated; 10 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Gelares [Artist Folder], 1905-1947 undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Genovés [Artist Folder], 1950 undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Giordan – Gomez, 1909-1942 undated; 20 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Gonzales – Valerio-Gutierrez, 1904-1953 undated; 29 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Gols, John [Artist Folder], 1920-1938 undated; 11 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Guezala [Artist Folder], 1918-1920 undated; 13 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Helcelet – Krick, undated; 16 items (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Hidalgo [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Izaguirre [Artist Folder], undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Julibert [Artist Folder], 1919 undated; 6 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Juncedre [Artist Folder], 1945 undated; 5 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Junod [Artist Folder], 1918 undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Kunst [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - L – Leal, undated; 13 items (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Lederer – Loll, undated; 13 items (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Lambert [Artist Folder], 1945; 1 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Larkavisky [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Leon, F. [Artist Folder], 1922; 2 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Leone [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Lhandy [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Lhorens [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Llongveras [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Llobert [Artist Folder], 1946 undated; 2 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Llod [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Llorens [Artist Folder], 1946; 1 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Lopes – Luch, 1901-1962 undated; 23 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Losilla [Artist Folder], 1947 undated; 2 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Luz [Artist Folder], 1947; 1 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - M – Mallos, 1931 undated; 21 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Machado, J. [Artist Folder], 1936 undated; 3 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Malgrave [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Mallol [Artist Folder], 1947-1951; 3 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Mansana – Martin, undated; 21 items (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Marcel [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Marengo [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Marquis [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Martinez – Mazanas, 1949 undated; 31 (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Martinez, A. [Artist Folder], 1946 1952; 2 (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Massansalvador, J. [Artist Folder], undated; 3 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - Mayer [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Medinacelli – Mitjavila, 1947 undated; 17 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Melcher [Artist Folder], 1949; 1 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Mendez, A. [Artist Folder], 1948 1950 undated; 8 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Meseguer [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Mesíras [Artist Folder], 1905; 1 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Miciano [Artist Folder], 1955 1958; 2 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Miracle, F. & other Miracles [Artist Folder], 1904-1940 undated; 43 (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - Molas – Montserrat, 1920 undated; 23 (Box 5, Folder 117)
  - Molas, E. [Artist Folder, undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 118)
  - Mollevaut [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - Monsalvatje [Artist Folder 1 of 3], 1922-1940 undated; 20 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Monsalvatje [Artist Folder 2 of 3], 1905-1912 undated; 25 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Monsalvatje [Artist Folder 3 of 3], 1905-1925 undated; 27 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Monso – Moran, 1902-1912 undated; 25 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Motos – Muntadas, undated; 11 items (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Moya [Artist Folder], 1905; 2 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - N – Nuñez, 1908-1955 undated; 13 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Nadal [Artist Folder], 1946 undated; 4 (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Navarra [Artist Folder 1 of 4], 1939-1947; 25 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Navarra [Artist Folder 2 of 4], 1946 undated; 25 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Navarra [Artist Folder 3 of 4], 1939-1953; 23 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Navarra [Artist Folder 4 of 4], undated; 21 (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Nebot [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - de Net [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Nestor [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Noguesras [Artist Folder], 1924; 2 (Box 6, Folder 135)
  - O – R. Oliva, undated; 8 (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - V. Oliva – Olivera, 1949 undated; 14 (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Oliver – Ovies, 1902-1950 undated; 6 (Box 6, Folder 138)
  - Orduña [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Orty, J. [Artist Folder], 1955; 1 (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Osiander, E. [Artist Folder], 1958 undated; 6 (Box 6, Folder 141)
  - P – Parrañaga, 1919-1947 undated; 20 (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Paniego, L. [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 6, Folder 143)
  - Parera – Peña, 1902-1949 undated; 19 (Box 6, Folder 144)
  - Pascual, J. [Artist Folder], 1947; 1 (Box 6, Folder 145)
  - Pelegri, M. [Artist Folder], 1950; 1 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Pellejero, M. [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Pereira – Petra, 1902-1948 undated; 16 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Perez Cobos, A. [Artist Folder], 1937; 1 (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Perpinyá [Artist Folder], undated; 1 item (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Piedade, A. [Artist Folder], 1931; 1 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Piedade – Prats, 1898-1919 undated; 21 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Pinell, O. [Artist Folder], 1954-1959 undated; 16 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Plaas [Artist Folder], 1910; 1 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Pla Dalmau [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Pla Palleja [Artist Folder], 1959; 1 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Plana, J. [Artist Folder], 1902 undated; 3 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Planas, O. [Artist Folder], 1946 undated; 3 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Port [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - Prat, P. [Artist Folder], 1946; 2 (Box 7, Folder 160)
  - Prenafeta – Puiz, 1903 undated; 17 (Box 7, Folder 161)
  - Puig, M [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Puntis, N. [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Queralt – Quirno, 1936 undated; 4 (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - R – Rivero, 1901-1958 undated; 24 (Box 7, Folder 165)
  - Ramirez [Artist Folder], 1952; 1 (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Renart, J. [Artist Folder 1 of 2], 1905-1949 undated; 25 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Renart, J. [Artist Folder 2 of 2], 1904-1940 undated; 20 (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Ricart [Artist Folder], 1943 undated; 10 (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Ridaura [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 7, Folder 170)
  - Riquer [Artist Folder 1 of 5], 1902-1904 undated; 25 (Box 7, Folder 171)
  - Riquer [Artist Folder 2 of 5], 1902-1950 undated; 25 (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Riquer [Artist Folder 3 of 5], 1901-1902 undated; 30 (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Riquer [Artist Folder 4 of 5], 1901-1905 undated; 25 (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Riquer [Artist Folder 5 of 5], 1900-1906 undated; 38 (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Roca – Rothvoss, 1904 undated; 25 (Box 7, Folder 176)
  - Roca [Artist Folder], undated; 7 (Box 7, Folder 177)
  - Roig [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 7, Folder 178)
  - Ros [Artist Folder], 1950 1952; 2 (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - di Rosana [Artist Folder], 1913; 1 (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Rossell, R. [Artist Folder], 1946-1952; 7 (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - Roumald, M. [Artist Folder], 1948; 1 (Box 8, Folder 182)
  - Rovira – Rumina, 1912-1956 undated; 12 (Box 8, Folder 183)
  - de Rubinat [Artist Folder], 1901-1932 undated; 16 (Box 8, Folder 184)
  - Ruperez [Artist Folder], undated; 3 (Box 8, Folder 185)
  - S – Sandoval, 1912-1918 undated; 19 (Box 8, Folder 186)
  - Sabate [Artist Folder], 1912-1918 undated; 5 (Box 8, Folder 187)
  - Sabell [Artist Folder], 1952-1963 undated; 24 (Box 8, Folder 188)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 1 of 7], 1938-1956 undated; 25 (Box 8, Folder 189)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 2 of 7], 1950-1953 undated; 25 (Box 8, Folder 190)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 3 of 7], 1958 undated; 26 (Box 8, Folder 191)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 4 of 7], 1947-1952 undated; 30 (Box 8, Folder 192)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 5 of 7], 1950-1953 undated; 36 (Box 8, Folder 193)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 6 of 7], 1953 undated; 14 (Box 8, Folder 194)
  - Saez [Artist Folder 7 of 7], 1956 undated; 17 (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Salis [Artist Folder], 1903 undated; 3 (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Saló [Artist Folder], 1947-1948 undated; 9 (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Salvatierra [Artist Folder 1 of 2], 1956 undated; 25 (Box 8, Folder 198)
  - Salvatierra [Artist Folder 2 of 2], 1950-1951 undated; 21 (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Sando [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 200)
  - Sangallo – Sedó, 1900-1956 undated; 40 (Box 9, Folder 201)
  - Sedó – Sigalés, 1916-1952 undated; 25 (Box 9, Folder 202)
  - Sigalés – Soroa, 1911-1919 undated; 24 (Box 9, Folder 203)
  - Soroa – Surya, 1950-1956 undated; 15 (Box 9, Folder 204)
  - Tacconet, E. [Artist Folder], 1914; 1 (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Tadey [Artist Folder], undated; 2 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Talpa – Torras, 1919-1949 undated; 20 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Teijeiro [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - Thorvis [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Todde [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Tolleri [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Torre, E. de la [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - Torrentes – Tríadó, 1902-1958 undated; 28 (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - Torres, J. [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 1 of 13], undated; 20 (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 2 of 13], 1902-1918 undated; 33 (Box 9, Folder 216)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 3 of 13], 1902 undated; 24 (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 4 of 13], 1904-1905 undated; 28 (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 5 of 13], undated; 27 (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 6 of 13], undated; 25 (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 7 of 13], undated; 25 (Box 9, Folder 221)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 8 of 13], 1902-1938 undated; 30 (Box 10, Folder 222)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 9 of 13], 1915 undated; 25 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 10 of 13], 1919 undated; 26 (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 11 of 13], 1919 undated; 25 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 12 of 13], undated; 25 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Tríadó [Artist Folder 13 of 13], 1922 undated; 15 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Trias, B. [Artist Folder], 1949 1951 undated; 5 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - V – Varona, undated; 26 items (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - Vasconcellos – Villar, 1905-1984 undated; 30 (Box 10, Folder 230)
  - Victorio, F. [Artist Folder], 1946 1948 undated; 4 (Box 10, Folder 231)
  - Vidal, J. [Artist Folder], 1934 undated; 2 (Box 10, Folder 232)
  - Vila, J. [Artist Folder], 1918-1919 undated; 7 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Vila, Q. [Artist Folder], 1956; 1 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - Vilanova [Artist Folder], 1956; 1 (Box 10, Folder 235)
  - Villalobos [Artist Folder], 1955; 1 (Box 10, Folder 236)
  - Villela [Artist Folder], 1942; 1 (Box 10, Folder 237)
  - [Vilas], D. [Artist Folder], undated; 1 (Box 10, Folder 238)
  - Viñas – Zarragat, undated; 9 (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - Viola [Artist Folder], 1910 1911 undated; 7 (Box 10, Folder 240)
  - Vizcaino [Artist Folder], 1955-1959 undated; 18 (Box 10, Folder 241)
  - Xam [Artist Folder], 1948 undated; 8 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Zuj, M. [Artist Folder], 1948; 2 (Box 10, Folder 243)
- Bookplates – To be filed, 1620-1902; Series II
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains bookplates previously housed in a folder marked "To be filed, A-L and L-Z."
  Arranged alphabetically by patron's last name.
  - de Abreu – Arellano, 1775-1850 undated; 16 (Box 11, Folder 244)
  - de Arteaga – Lazcano-Carnvajal, 1759-1902 undated; 20 (Box 11, Folder 245)
  - Casal – Marques de la Fuensanta del Xalle, 1750-1765 undated; 23 (Box 11, Folder 246)
  - Gago – Loustaunau, 1649-1890 undated; 19 (Box 11, Folder 247)
  - de Luna – de Navarra, 1643-1850 undated; 18 (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - O'Donell – Ruero, 1683-1815 undated; 21 (Box 11, Folder 249)
  - Marques de San Juan – Velasco, 1638-1750 undated; 21 (Box 11, Folder 250)
  - Velazquez – Zoya, 1620-1795 undated; 12 (Box 11, Folder 251)
- Bookplates – Miscellaneous, 1500-1954; Series III
  This series contains various groupings of bookplates, including royal Spanish examples, Spanish and Portuguese materials from the A. Bernard C. K. Keeves collection, and universal as well as some unidentified bookplate specimens.
  - Royal [1 of 2], 1620-1795 undated; 20 (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Royal [2 of 2], undated undated; 9 (Box 11, Folder 253)
  - Unidentified, undated; 13 items (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - Keeves Collection (Unidentified), 1500-1840 undated; 20 (Box 11, Folder 255)
  - Keeves Collection (Unidentified), 1590-1855 undated; 21 (Box 11, Folder 256)
  - Keeves Collection (Old Portuguese), 1640-1850 undated; 19 (Box 11, Folder 257)
  - Lafont – Matue, 1905-1925 undated; 30 (Box 12, Folder 258)
  - Medinacelli – Oliva, 1925 undated; 28 (Box 12, Folder 259)
  - Oliva – Pires, 1939 undated; 20 (Box 12, Folder 260)
  - Pires – Rull-Zayas, 1910-1954 undated; 25 (Box 12, Folder 261)
  - Rumina – Saez, 1931-1954 undated; 20 (Box 12, Folder 262)
  - Salvatierra – Zutis, 1911-1939 undated; 29 (Box 12, Folder 263)
  - "Spanish Anonymous" [1 of 2], 1850-1952 undated; 60 (Box 12, Folder 264)
  - "Spanish Anonymous" [2 of 2], 1920-1921 undated; 67 (Box 12, Folder 265)
- Bookplates – Barcelona, 1918-1962; Series IV
  This series contains materials that were grouped together in a file labeled "Barcelona." It includes inventories, exchange requests with accompanying bookplates, and bookplate portfolios and related ephemera from the 1958 Ex-Libris Congress held in Barcelona.
  - Miscellaneous (Letters, Inventory), 1957 1958 undated; 13 (Box 13, Folder 266)
  - VI Congreso Europeo de Exlibris, 1958; 21 (Box 13, Folder 267)
  - VI Congreso Europeo de Exlibris, 1958; 23 (Box 13, Folder 268)
  - Asociación de Exlibristas de Barcelona, 1959; 6 (Box 13, Folder 269)
  - Miscellaneous (Bookplates, Letters), 1919-1962 undated; 17 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - Pepita Pallé Barcelona: Her Bookplates, 1918-1962 undated; 64 items contained in 1 folio (Box 13, Folder 271)
    Folio contains an inventory and 60-plus bookplates designed for Pepita Pallé by various artists, dating from 1946-1962.